# Alejandro Núñez Pérez

 • Granada, Spain
 • ☑ alejnp@proton.me
 • ☐ linkedin.com/in/alejnp
 • ☐ github.com/alxe

## About Me \_\_\_\_\_

Hello! I'm Alejandro, a Software Engineer with over five years of experience across multiple roles and a hunger for learning new things.

When it comes to work, I am most interested in information transformation pipelines, distributed systems, and knowledge sharing. Particularly, I have a soft spot for Java and the JVM ecosystem.

Personally, my hobbies include finances, anything related to maps, and board games.

### Skills and Qualifications \_\_\_\_\_

**Customer Support Veteran:** Extensive experience in managing customer expectations, providing technical solutions, and ensuring customer satisfaction in high-pressure scenarios

**Software Development Expertise:** Well-versed in development, testing, packaging and distribution for diverse projects and applications. Particularly experienced in Java, Python and C/C++ ecosystems

**Distributed Systems and Networking:** Strong understanding of distributed systems, networking protocols, and real-time data processing, with hands-on experience in implementing and debugging complex systems

**Quality Assurance Focus:** Strong advocate for test-driven and quality-oriented development, with the ability to adapt and balance quality considerations against project constraints

## Professional Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Senior Software Engineer**, Real-Time Innovations – Hybrid (Granada or Remote) Apr 2024 – present Part of the API, later GPP development teams focused on the Connext Professional products.

- · Maintained an internal, distributed testing Python framework for RTI products.
- Improved the Java API by introducing new features to align with other APIs. Also identified memory leaks and fixing >90% of the reported issues.
- Developed a new internal web server for storing and visualizing performance data using FastAPI, with a MongoDB database backend.

**Software Engineer**, Real-Time Innovations – Hybrid (Granada or Remote)

Nov 2019 – Apr 2024

Part of the Support team, providing low-level, technical support to worldwide customers across multiple industry verticals, with a focus on the EMEA and APAC regions.

- Resolved customer time-sensitive escalations on critical deployments.
- · Maintained multiple branches of support releases, built and delivered patches.
- Mentored new hires and interns, providing training on troubleshooting and debugging techniques.

#### Education \_\_\_\_\_

MBA Ediae, Cámara de Comercio, Business – Granada, Spain Nov 2024 – present General MBA focused on wide-area knowledge of managing a business, including Strategy, Marketing and Finances.

**BS** Universidad de Granada, Computer Science – Granada, Spain Sept 2015 – Sept 2019 Basics of Computer Science, including Algorithm Design, Data Structures, Networking and Distributed Systems.

· Honors in Modern Multi-paradigm Programming.